- 라일리 상등병님
- 응?
- Corporal Reilly?
- Yeah?
오늘 밤 순찰하는 병사가 있습니까?
Do we have any patrols
running perimeter tonight?
내가 아는 한 없는데, 왜?
Not that I'm aware of. Why?
뭔가 보입니다
Because I think
I've got something.
넌 항상 그러지 않나
You always got something.
아닙니다, 이번엔 분명히
뭔가 있습니다
No, this is definitely something.
적색. 열 감지가 잡힙니다
Red read.
Warm blood.
사람 같습니다
I think it's human.
식서스가 분명해, 하나가 보이면
분명히 더 있는 거다
That's gotta be a Sixer. And if there's one,
there's bound to be more.
중위님께 보고하는 게 좋겠다
Better get Wash on the line.
자막제작 - ND24 클럽 자막팀
(http://cafe.naver.com/nd24club)
조건부 배포 / 수정금지
배포시 자막 출처를 꼭 밝혀주세요
저기다! 어서 가!
There! Go, go, go!
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON FOX
2011/10/17
동영상 정보
HDTV-LOL / 349M
싱크편집
박창균(fasces@paran.com)
한글번역
강진희(cuttyjini@naver.com)
던햄, 돌아서 가!
Dunham, go around. Go!
저기다, 싸이카 1호
그쪽으로 간다
There. Biker One,
coming your way.
Terra Nova
1x05 The Runaway
하나도 안 아플 거야
This won't hurt a bit.
- 얘야
- 얘야, 괜찮아
- Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Hey, it's okay.
- 진정해, 알겠어?
- 아무도 널 해치지 않아
- Calm down, all right?!
- Nobody's gonna hurt you!
워시, 아이는 어디 있나?
Wash? Where is she?
바로 저기 있습니다
She is right over there.
- 여기 있어요?
- 네
- She's here?
- Yeah.
안녕
Hi.
아이가 겁먹었어요
She's terrified.
전부 다 나가 주시고
I need to get
everybody out of here
우리끼리 있게 해 주세요
아시겠죠?
and just clear some
space for us, all right?
중령님도요
That includes you.
이해하지만 아이와
얘기하고 싶소, 박사
Understood, but I want
to talk to her, Doc.
알겠으니까, 잠깐만 아이와
단둘이 있을게요, 됐죠?
Okay, just give me
a few minutes alone with her, all right?
안녕, 꼬마야
겁먹지 마
Hey, little one,
don't be frightened.
아무도 널 해치지 않을 거야
No one's gonna hurt you.
난 섀넌 박사란다
I'm Dr. Shannon.
여기가 어디인지 아니?
Do you know where you are?
탁자 밑이요
Under a table.
아줌마 친구들은 미안하구나
Sorry about my colleagues.
널 겁주려고 그런 건
아닐 거야
I don't think they meant
to scare you.
나한테 주사를 놓으려고 했어요
They want to give me a shot.
주사 싫어요
Don't like shots.
이름이 뭐니?
Do you have a name?
말하면 가도 돼요?
If I tell you, can I go?
내가 널 좀 살펴보면
그럴 수도 있지
Perhaps. Once I've taken
a look at you.
여기로 나와서
아줌마랑 얘기할까?
Why don't you come out
here and talk to me?
싫어요
No.
좋아
Okay.
주사 안 놓는다고
약속하면 어떨까?
What if I promised
no shots,
이것만 할게
just this?
그냥 불빛이야
아프지 않을 거란다, 봐
It's just a light.
Won't hurt you. Look.
그러면 이제 나올래?
Would you come out then, yeah?
좋아
Okay.
됐다
가방을 잃어버렸어요
I lost my bag.
정글에서?
In the jungle?
저를 막 쫓아 와서
가방을 떨어트렸어요
They were chasing me,
and I dropped it.
쫓기는 거 싫어요
Don't like chases.
괜찮아
Well, that's okay.
네 가방 찾으러
사람을 보내면 돼
We can get somebody
to go look for your bag.
이제 네 이름 말해줄래?
So, you gonna tell me your name?
리아 마르코스요
Leah Marcos.
집이나 캠프에서
널 기다리는 사람이 있니?
So, do you have somebody waiting
for you back at home...or camp?
엄마는?
What about your mother?
죽었어요
Dead.
윤활막..
Pleural sar...
윤활막육종?
Pleural sarcoma?
안됐구나
I'm sorry.
아버지는?
And your father?
슬래셔가 죽였어요
Slasher got him.
미라 아줌마가 그런 일이
종종 있다고 했어요
Mira says it happens sometimes.
누구 배고픈 사람?
Anybody hungry?
뭐 먹은 지 오래됐니?
Been a while since you've eaten?
먹다 남은 것만 먹었어요
그래서 도망쳤어요
Only get scraps.
That's why I ran away.
할머니랑 살 거예요
I'm gonna stay with my nana.
할머니한테는
음식이 항상 많았어요
She always had a lot of food.
할머니가 테라 노바에 사시니?
Does Nana live in Terra Nova?
뉴베리 에비뉴 9007번지
9007 Newberry Avenue,
뉴 텍사스 10지구 C동이요
apartment C, district ten,
New Texas.
관문을 찾으려고 했는데
반대로 와 버렸어요
I tried to find the portal,
but I got turned around backwards.
어느 쪽이에요?
Which way is it?
밥 마저 먹거라
Finish your food.
나중에 얘기할 거다
We'll talk about it later.
여기는 테일러, 말하라
Taylor here.
Talk to me.
경계 지역 이상 없습니다, 오버
Perimeter is clear, over.
알았다, 통신 끝
Copy that.
Taylor out.
테일러 중령님이세요?
Commander Taylor?
그게 나란다
That's would be me.
아저씨 나쁜 사람이에요
You're the bad man.
아저씨는 네가 기억나는구나
You know, I remember you.
마르코스야, 리아 마르코스
Marcos. Leah Marcos.
널 본지 오래되었구나
Been a long time
since I've seen you.
마지막 봤을 때
넌 이 정도였어
Last time I saw you,
you were just about that big.
땅콩만 했지
You were just a peanut.
컸는데요
I grew.
그랬구나
So you did.
내가 테라 노바 주민의 이름을
You know, there was a time
전부 알던 때가 있었단다, 남자
when I knew everybody's name
in Terra Nova: man,
여자, 땅콩도
woman and peanut.
남동생이 있었어
맞지? 샘이지
You got a brother,
right? Sam.
체질량지수가
제 생각보다 낮으니
Well, her BMI is lower
than I'd like it to be,
수액을 좀 주고 싶긴 하지만
and I'd like to get
some more fluids in her,
대체로 건강해요
but she's generally healthy.
저 갈래요
I'm going now.
- 리아!
- 워!
- Leah!
- Whoa!
- 잠깐만, 얘야
- 괜찮아, 리아
- Hold on there, kiddo.
- It's okay, Leah, Leah.
아줌마 남편이야
짐 아저씨야
This is my husband, right?
This is Jim.
괜찮아, 알겠지?
You're all right, okay?
잘 듣거라, 리아
Listen, Leah,
너한테 해 줄 이야기가 있다
we got something
we need to tell you.
잘 들어야 한다, 리아?
I need you to listen
to me carefully, Leah, okay?
관문 알지?
그게 양 방향이 아니야
You know the portal?
It doesn't go both ways.
네?
What?
일단 통과해 오면
되돌아갈 수는 없단다
Once you come through,
you can't go back.
거짓말이에요!
You're lying!
미안하다, 아가
I'm sorry,
sweetheart.
그럼 할머니 보러
못 가는 거예요?
So I can't go see my grandma?
유감스럽게도 그렇단다
No, I'm afraid you can't.
그럼 이제 난 어디로 가요?
Where do I go now?
여기 있을 수 없어요
나쁜 사람이 있잖아요
I can't stay here,
not with the bad man.
미라 아줌마한테도 못 돌아가요
And I can't go back to Mira's.
미라 아줌마는..
She'll...
도망쳤다고 벌 줄 거라고요
she'll hurt me
for running away.
아주 강단 있는
꼬마 아가씨야
That is one tough young lady.
생각해 봐, 정글 어디서부터
헤집고 다녔는지 누가 알겠나
Imagine that, humping through the jungle
on her own from God knows where.
여기까지 온 걸 보면
놀랍죠
It's amazing she made it
as far as she did.
우리한테 유리한 일이
될 수도 있어
You know, this could turn out
to be a very good thing for us.
무슨 말씀이십니까?
How do you mean?
우리는 식서스에 대한
정보가 필요하잖나
Oh, we need intel on the Sixers.
은신처가 어디인지?
Where is it they hide out?
테라 노바에 심어 놓은
첩자가 누군지?
Who's their inside man
here in Terra Nova?
리아는 그저 아이인데
알아봤자 얼마나 알겠습니까?
But she's just a kid.
I mean, how much could she really know?
우리를 믿게 하고 집처럼 편하게 해주면
또 모르는 일이지
Well, we won't know anything
till we gain her trust, make her feel at home.
아이는 어떻소?
How's she doing?
아직 긴장한 상태지만
You know, she's still upset,
간신히 진정시킨 것 같아요
but I think I managed
to calm her down.
박사는 아이를
잘 다루는 것 같소
You do seem to have
that effect on her.
아이가 살 집을
마련해 줄 때까지
You know, till we find her
a permanent place to live,
머물 곳이 필요할 텐데
she's gonna need
somewhere to stay.
저희랑 지내도 됩니다
Well, she can stay with us.
그렇지, 짐?
Right, Jim?
엘리자베스?
Elisabeth?
이제 우리 식구가
6명인 거야?
So, what, our
family's six now?
그렇잖아
Come on.
조쉬 방에서 지내면 돼
She can have Josh's room.
조쉬는 당분간
소파에서 자면 되고
He'll be fine
on the couch for a while.
그러면 됐군
It's settled then.
아주 좋소
Very good.
왜 내 방을 내줘야 하는데?
Why do I have to
give up my room?
조이는 6살이고
난 여자잖아, 오빠
Because Zoe's six
and I'm a girl, Josh.
그게 다 무슨 상관인데?
What does that have
to do with anything?
왔나 보다, 잘해
Okay, shush. That's them.
Be nice.
얘들아
Hey, everyone.
조쉬랑 매디야
Come and meet Josh and Maddy
조쉬는 어디 있어?
Where's Josh?
저기 있어요
Stand there.
얘들아, 여기는 리아 마르코스야
Hey. Everyone,
this is Leah Marcos.
리아, 아줌마 아들 조쉬야
Leah, this is our son, Josh.
안녕, 잘 왔어
Hello. Welcome.
여기는 큰 딸 매디야
And this is our eldest daughter, Maddy.
내일 아줌마랑 의무실에서
실습을 시작할 거란다
She's gonna be starting an apprenticeship
at the infirmary with me tomorrow.
안녕
Hi.
여기는 막내딸 조이야
And this is our
youngest, Zoe.
조이는 벌레 먹는
식물도 키운단다
You know, Zoe's got
a plant that eats bugs,
그리고 남는 시간에
이 장난감 공룡도 만들어
and in her spare time,
she makes these toy dinosaurs.
꽤 멋지지?
Pretty cool, huh?
욕실은 저쪽이고
Well, uh, bathroom's through there.
부엌은 저기란다
And the kitchen's over there,
또 배고플지 몰라서 말이야
in case you get
hungry again.
어디서 자게 될지 보러 갈래?
Um, do you want to see
where you're gonna sleep?
괜찮아, 그냥 조명이야
It's okay.
It's only light.
여기 이걸로
Here,
침대 정리해
make the bed up.
우리..
We should...
리아가 자게 둬야겠다
probably let her sleep.
그래
Yeah, okay.
애 가방이 어떻게 생겼는지도
모릅니다
I don't even know what the kid's bag
is supposed to look like.
내가 추측해 볼까?
더러울 거야
My guess? Dirty.
여기 찾았습니다!
Hey, found it!
여기 줘 봐
Give it here.
귀엽네
Cute.
어서 덤벼!
Come on!
아직도 테일러의
뒤처리나 하고 있군
Still doing Taylor's dirty work.
애를 어떻게 한 거야?
What have you done with her?
리아는 어젯밤에 잘 잤어?
How'd Leah sleep last night?
14시간을 쭉 잤어
Oh, she was out cold
for 14 hours.
샤워를 안 하려고 했고
And she refused
to take a shower.
온수가 무서운가 봐
Apparently, she's afraid
of hot water.
잘됐네요, 바꾸면 되겠어요
Oh, nice.
Maybe can we trade.
리아는 우리랑 살고
매디는 식서스랑 살러 가고요
Leah can stay with us and Maddy
can move in with the Sixers.
뜨거운 물로 다들
샤워 더 할 수 있잖아요
More hot showers for everyone.
저한테는 윈윈 같은데요
Sounds like a win-win to me.
안녕히 주무셨어요
Good morning.
노란색이 잘 받는 것 같구나
I think yellow's your color.
노란색 싫어요
가려워요
Don't like yellow.
Itches.
좋아
Okay.
아침 먹을래?
Breakfast?
머리는, 매디?
What about the hair, Maddy?
하나씩 해요, 엄마
빗을 던져 버렸거든요
Baby steps, Mom.
She threw a brush at me.
아
Oh.
짐, 오늘 애들 볼 수 있어?
Jim, can you look after
the girls today?
아니, 중령님 만나러 가야 해
No. Gotta go see Taylor.
얘기할 게 몇 가지 있으신가 봐
A few things he wants
to talk about.
오래 걸리진 않을 거야
Shouldn't take long.
그런데 난 매디랑 온종일
병원에 있을 거야
But I've got Maddy with me
at the hospital all day.
- 그럼, 조쉬는?
- 네?
- Okay. Uh, Josh?
- Yeah?
내가 올 때까지 리아와 조이를
좀 봐, 몇 시간 안 걸린다
Need you to babysit Leah and Zoe
till I get back. Few hours tops.
얘들이랑 제가 뭘 해요?
What am I supposed
to do with them?
생각해 봐
Think of something.
재밌게 있어라
Have fun!
자..
So...
상태가 어떻지?
Okay, what
do we have here?
나지브 스와루프 씨예요
36세 남성으로
Rajiv Swarup,
36-year-old male.
오른팔에 열상이 있어요
Laceration to his right arm.
병원에서 진통제를 줬는데..
They gave me something
for the pain.
아직도 엄청 아픕니다
It still hurts
like a son of...
제가 좀 볼게요
Let's take a look.
좋아요
Okay...
어쩌다 다치셨죠?
How'd this happen?
자동 쟁기가 멈춰서
고치려 했는데
The autoplow jammed up.
I tried to fix it.
제 팔이 이렇게
소시지처럼 됐습니다
The next thing you know,
my arm's sausage.
- 매디, 와서 좀 봐
- 괜찮아요
- Ooh, Maddy, come take a look at this.
- Uh, that's okay.
그냥 여기 서서 볼게요
여기서요
I'll just stand over here
and observe... from over here.
조금만 하면 됩니다
Last little bit.
It's okay.
아마도 바로 여기로..
So that's probably
right into the...
새벽에 아이 가방 찾으러
워싱턴을 보냈어
I sent Washington out at dawn
to look for the girl's bag.
아이한테 좀
잘 보일까 생각했지
Thought maybe it'd
buy us some good will.
자네랑 하고 싶었던 것도
바로 이 이야기야
That's what I wanted
to talk to you about.
잘 잤나, 트레이스
고마워
Morning, Trace.
Thank you.
아이에게서 알아내기 이른 게
언제가 그렇다는 건가?
How soon is too soon to
start a debriefing?
오늘? 내일?
Today, tomorrow?
그것보다는 시간을 좀 더
주길 바랐는지도 모릅니다
Might want to give her
a little more time than that.
- 아내랑 얘기해 보겠습니다
- 알겠네
- I'll discuss it with Elisabeth.
- All right.
식서스다! 식서스다!
Sixers! Sixers!
경보를 울려!
자기 자리로 가!
Sound the alarm!
To your posts!
날 찾아온 거야
They've come for me.
여기 있으면 안전해, 리아
Hey, you're safe here, Leah.
테일러 중령님이 허락하기 전에
아무도 들어오지 못해
No one gets through the gates
unless Taylor says so.
리아 때문에 온 거야
They've come for the girl.
누군지 모르지만
첩자가 알려준 거야
Whoever they got on the inside
tipped them she's here.
문을 열어
Raise the gate.
무기 남는 거 있나?
You got a spare
one of those?
고맙네
Thanks.
그래?
So?
내 걸 가지고 있잖아
You have something
that belongs to me.
아이 다시 내놓으시지
I want her back.
그래서 내 부하들을
납치한 거야?
Is that why you abducted
my people?
그저 호의에 답할 뿐이지
테일러
Just returning the favor, Taylor.
- 아이가 자기 발로 왔어
- 당신 말 안 믿어
- The girl came to us.
- I don't believe you.
당신 부하들이
데려간 것 같은데
I think your
people took her.
포로로 잡혀 있다고 보거든
I think she's being held
as your prisoner.
그게 사실이 아닌 건
피차 아는 사실이잖아
I think we both know
that's not true.
당신 부하들 데려가고 싶으면
그 아이 내놔
You want your people back,
give me the girl.
이건 협상이 아니야
This is not a negotiation.
아이가 결정할 거야
The girl will decide
her own fate.
당신이랑 가고 싶다면
보내주겠다
If she wants to leave with you,
she's free to go.
그럼 여기 데려와서
한 번 알아보자고
Then bring her out here
and let's find out.
내 부하들 풀어주면
바로 그렇게 하지
As soon as you
release my people.
풀어줘
Let them go.
예?
What?
풀어주라고 했다
I said... let them go.
섀넌, 아이를 데려와
Shannon, bring the girl out here.
아빠가 오셔서
리아를 데려가셨어요
Dad came and got Leah.
뭐라고?
What?
미라가 리아랑
얘기하고 싶어한대요
Mira wants to talk to her.
조이 보고 있어
Okay, look after your sister.
- 하지만 엄마!
- 그냥 해, 매디
- But, Mom!
- Just do it, Maddy.
사실만 말하면 괜찮을 거야
Just tell the truth Leah.
It'll be okay.
리아, 날 봐
Leah, look at me.
집에 가고 싶다고 말해
Tell them you want to come home.
말하라고!
Speak!
난 도망친 거예요
I ran away.
같이 돌아가지 않을 거예요
I'm not going back with you.
여기 있고 싶어요
I want to stay here.
리아가 결정을 내렸군
She's made her decision.
여기 있을 거야
The girl stays.
그럼 데리고 있어
Keep her then.
나한테 아무것도 아니니까
She's nothing to me.
여기 문에 와서 위협한 게
This is the second time
you've come to my gates
이번이 두 번째야
and threatened the colony.
세 번째는 없을 거야
There won't be a third.
다음에는 전쟁이니까
Next time I'm going to war.
미라 도착시각부터
오늘 오전 9시 사이에
I want a list of everybody
who was outside the gates
문 바깥에 있던 사람들
모든 명단 가져와
from the time she got here
till 0900 this morning.
그 24시간 중 언젠가
Sometime in that
24-hour window,
첩자가 식서스와
연락을 취한 게 분명해
the spy must have got in
contact with the Sixers.
- 찾아보자고
- 그러죠
- Let's find him.
- Okay.
땅콩 아가씨
And you, hey, peanut,
아까 아주 잘했다
did great out there.
겁먹지도 않았지?
You weren't even scared,
were you?
그래 보였단다
No, I could see that you weren't.
주먹을 날리기라도
할 것처럼 보였지
You looked like you might even
throw a punch or something.
널 말릴까 생각했단다
Thought I'd have
to hold you back.
얼마나 센 지 한 번 보자
Hey, let's see
what you got, huh?
어서, 한 번 보자
Come on.
Let me have it.
본때를 보여줘
Whack him.
와우! 그럴 줄 알았어
Ow! I knew it.
아주 매운 주먹이구나
아주 세
That is a mean right hand
you've got there. Lethal.
계속 연습하거라
네가 18살이 되면
You keep practicing.
When you turn 18,
군복을 입게 해줄지도
모르겠구나
I'm might have to
put you in uniform.
나 군복 좋아해요
I like uniforms.
나에 대해서 아주 나쁜 얘기
들은 거 안다
Look, I know you've heard some
pretty terrible things about me
식서스와 저 밖에서 사는 게 어떤지
아저씨는 몰라
and I don't know how life is
out there with the Sixers,
하지만 리아
한 번 둘러보거라
but, Leah, take a look around.
사람들은 여기서 행복해
안전하지
People are happy here.
They're safe.
다들 집이 있고
아무도 음식찌꺼기 먹지 않아
Everybody's got a home
and nobody gets scraps.
나 음식찌꺼기 싫어요
I don't like scraps.
우리는 항상 움직여 다녀요
We move all the time.
그것도 난 싫어요
I don't like that either.
- 어디로 다녔는데?
- 되게 많아요
- Where do you move to?
- Lots of places.
미라 아줌마가 한 군데에
오래 있게 하지 않아요
Mira never lets us stay in
the same place for very long.
지도는 볼 줄 아니?
You know how
to read a map?
나 지도 좋아해요
I like maps.
아빠가 어떻게 보는지
알려줬어요
My dad taught me
how to read them.
슬래셔가 아빠를
먹어버리기 전에는요
Before the slasher ate him.
그렇구나
Yeah.
있잖니
I tell you what.
네가 좀 안정되고 나면
Maybe after you
get settled in,
아저씨랑 앉아서
you and I can sit down,
네가 지냈던 곳을
함께 살펴보자꾸나
take a look at some of
the places you've stayed.
캠프가 어디인지
네가 알려줄 수도 있겠지
Maybe you can show me
where your camp is.
그렇게 할래?
Deal?
아야!
Ow!
좋아, 안심이다
All right, I'm gonna
leave you in good hands.
그 명단 필요해
I need that list.
가자
Come on.
안녕, 아가야
Hey! Hello, there.
아저씨 기억나니?
아저씨는 기억나는데
Do you remember me?
'Cause I remember you.
꼬맹이 리아 마르코스
더는 꼬맹이가 아니구나
Little Leah Marcos.
Not so little anymore.
난 얼굴이나 이름은
절대 잊지 않는데 말이야
You know, I never
forget a name or a face,
어쩌다 보니
but somewhere along the line,
다리는 잊었구나
I forgot my legs.
어디서 다리가 자기들끼리
걸어다니는 걸 보면
So if you happen to see 'em
walking around without me,
내가 찾고 있다고 좀
전해 줄래?
could you tell 'em
I'm looking for 'em?
자
Hey...
테라 노바에 다시 온 걸
환영한다, 리아 마르코스
...welcome back to Terra Nova,
Leah Marcos.
리아 마르코스를 위해
To Leah Marcos.
집에 온 것을 위해
To coming home.
건배
Cheers.
내일은 네 머리에
빗질을 좀 할 수 있을까 하는데
Hey, maybe tomorrow
we can put a comb through your hair,
- 어떠니?
- 빗 싫어요
- you think?
- Don't like combs.
알겠다
Okay.
다들 의무실에서 첫날
매디가 어땠는지 봤어야 했어
You guys should have seen Maddy
on her first day in the infirmary.
아주 잘했지
She did a great job.
엄마 창고 다시 정리하고
환자 이름 말해 준 게
Yeah, well, all I really did was
reorganize your storage locker
다였는데 뭘요
and told you a patient's name.
아니, 우리 큰 딸을 위해
섀년 가의 차세대 의사지
No, to my oldest daughter.
the next doctor in the Shannon family.
동의해, 건배
Hear, hear. Cheers.
첩자 사냥은
어찌 되어 가고 있지, 섀넌?
So how's the mole hunt
going, Shannon?
진척상황을 보고해 보게
Give me an update.
오전 6시 반부터 정오까지
경계 광산 정비를 하던
Okay, there was a team
outside the gates doing
외부 팀이 한 팀 있었습니다
some perimeter mine repair
from 0630 to about noon:
미셸 투미와
넷 트렝인가요?
Michelle Toomey
and, uh, Nhat Trang?
아니야, 둘 다 내가 알아
No, I know 'em both.
아주 훌륭한 시민이야
거긴 괜찮아
Good solid citizens.
Nothing there.
과학부서에서 추가 현장 연구로
누군가를 데리고 나갔습니다
Okay, and Science Division had somebody out
following up on a field study.
CSO의 차를 타고 나갔습니다
로버트 스탠리네요
They took the CSO's rover;
Robert Stanley.
스탠리라고?
혼자 나갔나?
Stanley?
Did he go out alone?
네
Yeah.
- 가서 얘기해 보지
- 그 사람은 왜죠?
- Let's talk to him.
- Why him?
6번째 순례 때 여기 왔는데
He came in on
the Sixth Pilgrimage,
미라와 함께 떠나지 않았거든
but he didn't leave with Mira.
그 중 반 정도가 그랬지
Only about half of 'em did.
남은 사람들을 조사했지만
We investigated
those who stayed,
식서스와의 연관성은
찾지 못했어
but we couldn't find any
connection to the Sixers.
우리가 스탠리에게서
빠트린 게 있는지 모르지
Maybe we missed
something with Stanley.
그 문제는 다 끝난 걸로
알고 있었는데요
But I thought we'd
been over this.
내가 그만 하자고 할 때까지
계속 할 거야
And we'll keep going over it
till I say otherwise.
저는 이 왁스 이끼 현장 연구를
마무리하고 있었습니다, 이건..
I was completing my field
study on wax moss. This...
자네 현장 연구에는
관심 없어
I don't care
about your field study.
식서스에 대해서 얘기해 봐
Talk to me about
the Sixers.
식서스에 대해서는
아무것도 모릅니다
I don't know anything
about the Sixers.
어제 오전 11시에
무선 송신을 했잖아
Well, you made a radio transmission
at 1100 hours yesterday.
누구랑 연락했던 거지?
Who were you contacting?
연구실에요, 제가 늦을 거라고
알려 주려고요
The lab, to let them
know I'd be late.
중령님
Hey, Commander.
무슨 일로 여기까지 오셨습니까?
What brings you out here?
누군가 식서스에게
리아 얘기를 흘렸어
Somebody tipped the Sixers off
about the girl.
그게 롭이라고 생각하세요?
And you think it was Rob?
농담이시죠?
You can't be serious.
질문 몇 가지를 좀 할까 했지
I thought I'd ask
a few questions, yes.
실질적 증거라도 있으십니까?
And do you have any
actual evidence against him?
롭을 가둘만한 증거요
Enough to take him into custody?
이제 롭의 변호사라도 되나?
You his lawyer now?
아니오, 재밌게도
여기에는 그런 사람들 없죠
No. Funny enough, we don't have
any of those around here, do we?
말조심하게, 말콤
Tread carefully, Malcolm.
아니요, 그럴 맘 없습니다
No, I don't think I will.
이건 연좌제라고요
This is guilt by association.
그래서 롭이 식서스 편이 됐다면요?
So what if he came over
on the Sixth?
미라와 전혀 상관없던
상당수의 사람이 그랬잖습니까?
A lot of people did who have
nothing to do with Mira.
중령님 말씀처럼
그냥 질문만 한 겁니다, 진정하세요
Like the commander said,
we're just asking a few questions. Relax.
그래요, 2119년
에딘버러 청문회에서도
Yeah, and that's what they said
to my father
우리 아버지한테
바로 그렇게 말했었죠
at the Edinburgh Hearings of 2119.
그냥 질문만 한다고요
"Just asking questions."
그렇게들 시작합니다, 짐
That's how it starts, Jim.
잘난 척 좀 그만 하게, 말콤
Get off your high horse,
will you, Malcolm?
괜찮지, 롭?
여기는 언제 올라온 거야?
You're alright, Rob?
When did you get up here?
긴장하지 마
Don't be nervous.
네가 몇 학년에 적합한지
작은 시험 하나 보는 거야
It's just a small test to see
what grade level you'll do best in,
그리고 월요일에
등교 시작할 수 있어
and then, Monday,
you can start school.
재밌겠지?
Sounds fun, right?
걱정 말거라, 짐 아저씨가
몇 시간 있다가 데리러 오실 거야
Don't worry. Jim will be by
in a couple of hours to pick you up.
알겠지?
Okay?
고맙습니다
Thank you.
가거라
Bye.
너무 귀여워요
Aw.
She's so cute.
네 첫 등교 날 기억 나니?
Remember your first
day at school?
너무 가고 싶어했지
You couldn't wait
to get there.
네, 정말 좋았어요
Yeah, I loved it.
- 거짓말은 안 할게요
- 그래야 우리 딸이지
- Not gonna lie.
- That's my gal.
나중에 봐
I'll, uh, catch up
with you.
아버님
Mr. Shannon.
매디에 대해서
말씀드리고 싶었습니다
Sir, I... I was hoping to talk to you
about your daughter, Maddy.
매디에 대해서 뭘?
What about her?
아시다시피 지금 매디에게
구애하는 초기 단계인데
Well, as you know,
I've begun the initial stages of courting Maddy,
제가 궁금한 건, 제가..
and I was wondering
if I could...
잠깐만, 레놀즈
Excuse me, Reynolds.
내가 총을 소지하고, 욱하고
앙심을 잘 품는 거 알고 있지?
You are aware that I carry a gun,
have a quick temper and tend to hold grudges, right?
섀넌
Shannon.
포드 D-26 맥밀런 씨 집에
침입이 있었습니다
We had a break-in at the McMillen place.
Pod D-26.
가보죠
Let's move.
오늘 종일 일터에 있었는데
So I've been
at work all day.
집에 와보니
침입 흔적이 있더라고요
Came home and found
the place broken into.
그리고 이것도요
And then this.
안에 뭐가 있었습니까?
What was inside?
모릅니다
I don't know.
여기 구멍이 있는 것도
몰랐는데요
I didn't even know
there was a hole here.
잠깐 자리를 좀
피해주시겠습니까?
Could you, uh,
give us a minute?
- 네, 그럼요
- 감사합니다
- Yeah, sure.
- Thanks.
맥밀런 가족 전에 여기에
누가 살았는지 알아야 합니다
We need to find out who lived
here before the McMillens.
마루 밑에 뭐가 있었는지
아는지 봐야죠
See if they know anything about
what was buried under the floor.
- 그건 힘들 겁니다
- 왜죠?
- That's going to be tough.
- Why?
여기는 미라가 살던 곳이거든요
This used to be
Mira's old place.
당장 리어를 찾아야 합니다
We need to find Leah right now.
얘야
Hey.
여긴 무슨 일이니, 꼬마야?
What's going on here, kiddo?
그 부부 집에서
뭘 가지고 나온 거지, 리아?
What did you take
from that couple's house, Leah?
리아!
Leah!
그만! 멈춰!
Stop! Stop!
괜찮다, 괜찮아
It's okay.
그 가방을 주렴
Give me the bag.
도망칠 곳은 없어
There's nowhere to run.
의심할 여지가 없습니다
중령님
No doubt about it, Commander.
미라가 테라 노바에
침투하라고 리아를 보낸 겁니다
Mira sent her
to infiltrate Terra Nova.
우리한테 내내 거짓말을
하고 있었던 거죠
She's been lying to us
the whole time.
거의 연극이었던 겁니다
It was theater, more or less.
미라가 날 갖고 놀았군
Mira played me.
내가 아이를 받아들일 줄
알았던 거야
She knew I'd let
the kid in.
아이 말을 믿을 것도 알았고
Knew I'd believe
her story.
내가 아이를 보내지
않을 거란 것도 알았지
Knew I wouldn't send her away,
특히 식서스가 아이를 데려가려는
쇼한다면 더더욱
especially if the Sixers
made a show of trying to get her back.
완벽한 스파이입니다
She's the perfect spy.
동정심 일으킬 만큼 어리고
시킨 일을 할 만큼은 큽니다
Young enough to be sympathetic,
but old enough to be capable.
처음 기회를 잡고서
First chance she got,
그 집에 몰래 가서
이 용기를 가져왔습니다
she broke into that house
and grabbed this... container
이게 뭔지는 몰라도요
or whatever thing this is.
열립니까?
Does it open?
완벽히 막혀 있네
눈에 보이는 틈도 없어
Sealed shut,
no visible seams.
안은 빈 것 같고
Sounds like it's hollow.
- 아이에게 여는 법 물어보죠
- 모를지도 모르죠
- Ask her how to open it.
- She might not know.
실제로 안다고 해도
우리한테 말 안 할지도 모르지
Might not tell us
even if she does know.
아이 데려오게
Bring her in.
들어와
Come on.
앉거라, 얘야
Have a seat, kiddo.
왜 그랬는지는
물어보지 않을 거야
I'm not going to ask you
why you did what you did,
하지만 중령님과 내가
해야만 하는 일이니
but the Commander and
I have a job to do,
몇 가지 질문에
대답해 줬으면 한다
and we need you to
answer a few questions.
정직하게 대답해야 해, 알겠니?
We need you to be honest.
You understand?
꼬마 숙녀, 아저씨 보렴
Young lady, look at me.
이게 뭔지 아니?
You know what this is?
무기니?
Is it a weapon?
리아
Leah.
이제 거짓말은 안 된다, 알았지?
No more lies now, okay?
저기에 뭐가 들어 있니?
What's in there?
왜 미라가 저걸 원하니?
Why does Mira want it?
몰라요, 미라 아줌마가 얘기 안 했어요
I don't know. Mira didn't say.
그냥 가져오래서 그런 거예요
She just told me to get it,
so I did.
리아, 왜니?
왜 다 거짓말을 했니?
Leah, why? Why all the lies?
미라 아줌마가 제 남동생을
데리고 있으니까요
Because Mira's got my brother.
저 상자 훔쳐오지 않으면
동생을 해칠 거랬어요
And she said she was going to hurt him
if I didn't steal back that box.
사실이에요
I'm telling the truth.
아이를 파드 제로로 데려가
Take her to Pod Zero.
미라 아줌마한테 저 상자를
가지고 가야 해요
Please! I have to bring
that box back to Mira,
아니면 내 동생을
해칠 거라고요
or she'll hurt my brother.
샘을 해칠 거예요, 제발요!
She'll hurt Sam. Please!
정확한 정황을 파악 때까지
리아를 감금할 거야
We're going to detain her till we
figure out exactly what's going on here.
흥미롭네요
Fascinating.
매디
Maddy.
매디, 와서 한 번 봐라
Maddy, come and
take a look at this.
괜찮아요, 여기서도 좋아요
That's okay.
I'm good over here.
거기서는 아무것도
배울 수 없어, 와서 봐
Well, you can't learn anything
from over there. Come and look.
소포농포 병변이야
It's a vesiculopustular lesion.
- 온화하고 습한 기후에서 아주 흔해
- 싫어요
- Very common in warm, humid climate...
- No.
뭐가 걸리나?
Something on your mind?
동생 이야기가 사실이라면요?
What if she's telling the
truth about her brother?
혹시 모르니 사람들을 보내
확인해야 합니다
I mean, we...we should send a few people
to check it out just in case.
육감 때문에 여기 자원을
낭비하지는 않을 거네
I'm not going to expend
colony resources on a hunch.
미라가 이것도 예상했는지
모를 일이지
Mira might have planned this, too.
자네는 매복 속으로 곧장
걸어 들어가는 셈이야
You'd be walking right into an ambush.
하지만 저 밖에 다치는
아이가 있다면..
But if there's a kid out
there that's being hurt...
"있다면"이지, 증거라도 있다면
그건 또 별개의 문제야
"If." If I had some proof,
that would be one thing.
난 꼬마 여자애의 말을 믿었어
I got the word of a little girl
그 아인 나와
이곳 모든 사람을 속였네
who managed to deceive me and
every damn person in this colony.
- 압니다, 하지만 중령님..
- 대답은 '안 된다'네
- I know that, but, Commander...
- The answer is no.
이건 명령일세
That's an order.
그냥 두라고
Let it go.
아내와 아이들이 있으니
집에 가게
You got a wife, kids.
Go home.
미라가 정말로
리아 남동생을 해칠 것 같아?
You think Mira would really
hurt her little brother?
이제 리아 말이 진실인지
알 길이 없어
There's no way to know if she's
telling the truth about anything now.
전 산책 좀 나갈게요
I'm going to go for a walk.
오늘 의무실에서
좀 그랬거든
Not such a great day
in the infirmary today.
저 과잉성취자가 그냥
성취만 했나 봐요?
Did the overachiever just
kind of sort of achieve?
심장 절개 수술 대신에
맹장수술밖에 못 했데요?
Instead of open-heart surgery,
she could only do an appendectomy?
조쉬
Josh.
그만 해라
Stop talking.
최소한 제 방은
도로 찾았네요
At least I get my room back.
너무 자책하지 마
Hey, Don't beat yourself up.
리아가 우리를 실망시켰잖아
당신은 다 제대로 했어
Leah let us down.
You did everything right.
알아, 그냥 난 사람을
잘 볼 줄 안다고 생각했어
I know. I just thought I was a
better judge of character, you know?
나도 그랬는데, 뭐
Well, I thought I was, too.
사람들이 우리 가족을
이용하는 게 싫어
I don't like people taking
advantage of my family.
엄마, 아빠
리아가 이걸 남기고 갔어요
Mom, Dad.
Look what Leah left.
"죄송해요, 해야만 했어요"
"I'm sorry. I had to."
동생 얘기는
거짓말이 아니었네
So she wasn't lying about her brother.
정말로 애가 위험하다는 거네
Which means he really is in danger.
매디
Maddy.
- 안녕하세요
- 안녕
- Hey
지금 뭐 하는 중이야?
Are you doing anything right now?
네, 몇 가지 좀 사려고요
Yeah, I'm just picking up a few things.
너랑 하고 싶은 얘기가 있는데
I wanted to talk to you about something.
내가..
I, um...
너에 대한 내 의지를
분명히 하고 싶어, 매디 섀넌
I want to declare my intentions
for you, Maddy Shannon.
나한테 뭘 하고 싶다고요?
You want to do what to me?
너에게 구애를 할 거야
To court you.
구애요? 그러니까
데이트 같은 거요?
Court? You mean,l ike...like, date?
그래
Yes.
그럼 그냥 그렇게
말하지 그랬어요
Why didn't you just say that?
그건 제대로 된 방식이 아니니까
because that's not how it's done.
중령님 말씀이
널 특정한 방식으로 대하고
According to the commander, I have
to address you in a certain way,
그다음 네 아버지랑 얘기하고
다음에 너희 집에 들르고
and then speak with your father,
and then call at your house,
집 밖에서 널 기쁘게 해 줄
미리 준비한 일이나 이벤트로
and then have the honor of
escorting you to a planned activity
널 이끌어가는 영광을
갖는 거라고 하시던데
or event outside the home
that might please you.
예전에는 그렇게 했다고
People used to do it this way.
엄밀히 말하면
그럴 거예요
Well, technically,
they will do it that way.
그러니까 앞으로도요
You know, in the future.
하지만 그러고 나서
코르셋을 또 입을 거고요
But then again,
they'll also wear corsets.
그러면 내가 그 영광을
가져도 될까?
So... may I have the honor?
네, 네, 그래요
Yes.Yes, you may.
좋았어
Awesome.
- 그래?
- 네
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
오늘 정말 최악의 날이었거든요
'Cause I was just having
the worst day ever.
나한테 얘기해 봐
Well, tell me about it.
어디서부터 할까요?
Well, where should I start?
엄마 앞에서 환자한테
토할 뻔한 부분부터 할까요
The part where I almost puked on
a patient in front of my mother?
아니면 리아가..
Or the part where Leah just,
you know...
처음부터 해 봐
Start at the beginning.
시간 있어
I have time.
젠장
Crap.
새로 온 경찰이군
You're the new cop.
여기 어디요?
Where am I?
테일러가 보냈나?
Did Taylor send you?
리아 동생 때문에 왔소
당신이 해칠 거라던데
I came for Leah's brother.
She said you were gonna hurt him.
그 아이 말을 믿었고?
And you believed her?
꼭 해야 할 때만
거짓말을 했소
She only lied when she had to.
아이가 위험한 적은 없었어
The boy was never in danger.
아이에게 동기를
불어넣어 줘야 했을 뿐이야
I just needed to motivate her.
리아가 할 수 있는 일을 하도록
To get her to do what I knew she could.
상자 안에 든 게 뭐기에
그렇게 중요한 거요?
What's in the box that's so important?
여기 위 캐노피였다 이거요?
Right up here in the canopy, huh?
테일러 중령님이
못 찾았을 법도 하네
No wonder Taylor can't find you.
중령이 당신을 꽤
마음에 들어 한다 들었지
I hear he's taken quite a shine to you.
자기 이민지에 몰래 들어온
당신을 고려하면 사실 좀 놀랐달까
Have to say, I'm surprised, considering
the way you snuck into his colony.
테라 노바 내의 상황을
확실히 많이 알고 있군요
You sure know a lot about what
goes on inside of Terra Nova.
이런 생각이 들 정도요..
Almost makes me think, uh--
글쎄..
ooh, I don't know--
첩자나 뭐 그런 게
있는 것 같달까
you got yourself a spy or something.
내가 점쟁이인지도 모르지
Maybe I'm psychic.
그럴지도 모르죠
Maybe.
꼬마 아이를 보내는 대신에
당신 첩자를 시켜
Maybe you should've had
your spy get the box for you
상자를 가져오게 했어야지
instead of sending a little girl.
아니면 그 첩자인가를
노출할 위험은 감수하기 싫었나 보군?
Or did you not want to
risk exposing whoever it is?
왜 테일러가 당신을 그렇게
아끼는지 알겠군
I can see why Taylor values you so much.
그렇지
Yeah.
내가 한 번 중령님 목숨을
구해줬으니까
Well, that's 'cause I-I
got to save his life once.
사실 당신 덕분이었소
It was thanks to you,
as a matter of fact.
어떻게 보면
You know, in a way,
살린 게 다행이야
I'm glad you did.
카터가 죽였었더라면
Carter would've killed him,
순교자가 됐을 테니까
that would've made a martyr of him.
그러면 내 임무가
더 어려워졌을 테지
Which would only make my job harder.
당신 임무가 뭐요?
And what is your job?
테일러가 2149년의
최고위층 몇 명을 열 받게 했어
Taylor's pissed off some very
powerful people back in 2149.
그들은 죽이고 싶어해
They want him gone.
죽인다고?
Gone?
중령님이 없었다면 테라 노바는
지금만큼 오래가지 않았을 텐데요
If it wasn't for Taylor, Terra Nova
wouldn't have lasted as long as it has.
이민지를 지속시키려면..
If the colony survives...
섀넌, 그 "새로운 출발" 잡소리를
정말 믿는다는 건가?
Come on, Shannon, don't tell me you
believe in all that "starting over" crap!
그건 테라 노바의 존재 이유가 아니야
지금도 아니고, 그런 적도 없었어
That's not what Terra Nova's about.
Not now, not ever.
그럼 테라 노바 존재의
진짜 이유는 뭡니까?
Then what's Terra Nova really about?
알게 될 거야
You'll see.
자네도 역사의 잘못된 편에
서고 싶지는 않을 거야, 섀넌
But you don't want to be on the
wrong side of history, Shannon.
똑똑해지라고
Be smart.
당신 가족을 위해
옳은 일을 해
Do what's right for your family.
곧 우리가 테일러를
무너트릴 테니까
'Cause sooner or later,
we're going to take Taylor down.
이유가 뭡니까?
Why?
당신한테 뭐가 걸렸소?
What does it get you?
내 가족이 걸렸지
It gets me my family.
2149년에 내 딸이 있어
I have a daughter back in 2149.
시에나는 내가 떠날 때
네 살이었지
Sienna. She was four when I left.
내 임무를 해내면
I do my job...
그들은 내 딸을
다시 보게 해줄 거야
they make sure I get to see her again.
그 사람들이 누구요?
Who's they?
이제 보내 주지
You're free to go.
잠깐
Wait.
- 리아 누나!
- 샘!
- Leah!
- Sam!
괜찮을 거야
It's gonna be okay.
명령 불복종으로 자네를
쫓아내야 해, 섀넌
I ought to run you out of town
for disobeying an order, Shannon.
그래, 하지만 뭐 어떤가
가족 상봉을 시켜줬는걸
Yeah, but what the hell.
You reunited a family.
테라 노바 식구가 방금
공식적으로 두 명 늘었다고
Terra Nova just officially grew by two.
어떻게 거기서 아이를 데리고
빠져나온 거지?
How'd you make it out
of there with the boy?
미라가 보내줬습니다
Mira let us go.
미라 같지 않은 행동인데
전혀 그렇지 않아
Now, that doesn't sound like Mira.
Doesn't sound like her at all.
뭔가를 증명하려고
하는 것 같습니다
I think she was trying
to prove something.
식서스가 그렇게
나쁘지는 않다는 그런 거요
Like maybe the Sixers aren't so bad.
설득된 건가?
Were you convinced?
제 갈비뼈를 작살내지 않았다면
그랬을지도 모르죠
I might've been, if they
hadn't have busted up my ribs.
내가 알아야 할 말은
하지 않던가?
She say anything I should know about?
중령님 팬은 아니던데요
Well, she's not a fan of yours.
내가 알고 있는 거 말고
I meant something I don't already know.
아이를 보내 훔치려 한 상자가 뭔지
그것도 알고 싶었는데
I sure as hell would like to know what's
in that box she sent the kid here to steal.
열지는 못하셨죠?
No luck getting it open, huh?
가서 상처나 치료하지
Go get yourself bandaged up.
살아 있다는 걸
아내한테 알려 주라고
Let your wife know you ain't dead.
당신 치료 때마다
1테라씩 모은다면..
If I had a Terra for every time
I've had to put you back together...
내가 만날 다치기만
하는 사람처럼 말하네
You're making me sound
like Humpty Dumpty.
내가 의사랑 결혼한 건
다 그만한 이유가 있다고
You know, I married a
doctor for a reason.
잘했어
You did good.
미안
Sorry.
미안해
당신 덕에 리아는 괜찮을 거야
You know, Leah's going to
be all right because of you.
저기, 있잖아
3번째 순례로 온 한 여자가
Well, there's, um, there's a
lady from the Third Pilgrimage
리아를 장기간 데리고 있는데
관심이 있더라고
who's interested in
taking Leah on long-term.
몇 년 전에 남편을 잃었대
Lost her husband a few years back.
다행히 두 아이가 지낼 수 있겠네
Well, hopefully there's room for two.
매디는 어디 있어?
Where's Maddy?
용기와 배짱을 좀 모으라고
Well, to save her nerves and her stomach,
내가 실습에서 풀어줬어
I released her from her apprenticeship.
딸애가 꿈꾸며 살아가려는
의사로서 현실을 내가 생각지 못했어
Yeah, I don't think the reality of being a
doctor quite lived up to her romance of it.
실제에서는
피와 내장에 더 많잖아
More blood and guts in the real world.
유감이지만 여는 방법은
전혀 모르겠습니다
Sorry to say I haven't the
foggiest idea how to get it open.
- 전부 시도해 봤어요
- 계속해 보라고
- Tried everything.
- Well, keep trying.
이 망할 것 안에 든 걸 찾으러
미라가 아주 노력했잖나
Mira went a long way to get
whatever's inside the damn thing.
곧 다른 꾀를 낼 거야
Sooner or later,
she'll make another play.
안전하게 보관해 두게
Keep it safe.
누가 얘기를 좀 하고 싶답니다
Someone wants to talk with you.
내가 들은 얘기해 줄까?
You know what I heard?
네가 함께 지내게 될 아줌마가
아주 좋은 분이라는구나
I heard the lady that you're going
to be staying with is super nice.
그러니까..
So use your...
감사합니다
Thank you.
번역수정
박창균(fasces@paran.com)
한글교정
정규은(jgeun1007@naver.com)
자막제작 - ND24 클럽 자막팀
(http://cafe.naver.com/nd24club)
조건부 배포 / 수정금지
배포시 자막 출처를 꼭 밝혀주세요